

Willem J. Smith

Software Developer DETAILS

Email: jsjohn1951@gmail.com

Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/willems24

Residence: Abu Dhabi, UAE

PERSONAL SUMMARY

Passionate programmer having completed several projects relating to sorting algorithms, multithreading, and graphics implementation as part of my progression through the 42 Abu Dhabi cursus.

Enthusiastic student with a passion for learning and exploring unknowns, applying maths and logic operations to formulate algorithms.

Experienced in many different environments, adhering to teamwork, and maintaining quality standards to the best of my abilities.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Native Fluency in English and Afrikaans
- Intermediate Spanish
- Programming in C and C++
- · Programming in Java
- Programming in Shell script
- Object oriented programming
- · Makefile programming

SOFT SKILLS

- Leadership
- Public Speaking
- Adaptability
- Critical Thinking
- Problem Solving
- Multicultural Experience
- Self-motivated
- · Project Management

Objective

Motivated software developer looking to prove his skills in a position that will offer a rich learning experience. Eager to apply his skills and knowledge in software developing.

EDUCATION

Acellus Academy

(2016 - 2020)

High school honors diploma - Graduated with cumulative GPA of 3.92 11020 North Ambassador Drive, Suite 120 Kansas City, MO 64153

42AbuDhabi - Piscine

(May 16th, 2021 - June 10th, 2021)

Basics of programming in C language, simple algorithms, shell script, and Git repository usage.

Mina Zayed, warehouses district, Abu Dhabi, UAE

42AbuDhabi - 42 Cursus

(September, 2021 - Present)

Imperative programming, Parsing, Memory Management, Makefile implementation, Shell scripting, Unix, Graphics, Algorithms & Artificial Intelligence.

Notable projects completed in the cursus:

ft_printf

- push_swap
- get next line
- philosophers

so_long

minishell

Mina Zayed, warehouses district, Abu Dhabi, UAE

WORK EXPERIENCE

Junior Developer

Ammbr Limited, UAE

(July 20th, 2021 - Present)

Helped CTO define user experience flows and security frameworks.

Freelance Content Creator

(March, 2016 - Present)

Received custom gigs with unique specifications, compiled articles and webpages accordingly with respect towards specified deadlines, ensuring all requirements are met.

Volunteer Work

Voiceover Artist

Key2enable (2021)

Recorded voiceovers for Expressia, an application designed to assist in providing equal education opportunities for children of determination.

Twitch Stream Host and Moderator

42AbuDhabi (2022)

Hosted and Moderated live streams to introduce pisciners to the basics of programming.

Student Tutor

42AbuDhabi (2022)

Hosted sessions on how to create and implement Makefiles and memory management.